So hello my dear investors.  So
friends, in today's video we are going to talk
about ICICI Lambar.  So
friends, you already know that it is a general insurance company.
So friends, the
results of quarter one i.e. June quarter have been announced here yesterday.  That means it has been
announced here on 15th July.  So today we will talk about
how the company's performance has been in the June quarter, friends.  What kind of results have
come here and what
could be the future momentum of this stock price?
We are going to
discuss here a little about how this can happen.
Ok?  However, I will not give any estimates etc.
Friends, I will not give any recommendations etc. here.  Because
see, SEBI's guidelines are very
strong here.  Due to which
I will only tell you about the value.
Looking at that value, you will
decide yourself whether you want to
invest or not.
So see, there
is no important announcement here at the moment.  No
bonus split of any kind has been announced here.
Nor has any kind of
dividend been announced here in this quarter.
We do
n't see that happening here at the moment.  So friends, let us now
talk about how we see the company's
results coming out for this quarter.  First of all let's take a
look at sales.
Friends, the sales are around Rs 6396 crore, which was
around Rs 691 crore in the last quarter.
So definitely friends, we are seeing a
good growth in the June quarter as compared to the March quarter
because
what happens in the March quarter is that there are
huge targets on the
agents here, so due to which
friends, the reflection of that is
seen in the June quarter, if we
talk about June 2024, friends, the
sales were of 5601 crores, so definitely we are seeing a good growth as compared to the previous June quarter
and as compared to the March quarter as
well,
5415 crores, expenses of 981 crores,
friends, what has been the operating
profit here, the company has earned here, if we
talk about other incomes, then here you
can see that if we talk about interest from other income of 13 crores, then the
company has paid zero interest here.  What is the debt to equity
ratio here, friends
?  Here it is.  So
friends, now let's talk about net profit.
Friends, the net profit is Rs 747 crore, which
was Rs 510 crore in the previous quarter and if we
talk about the June quarter of 2024, it was
around Rs 580 crore.  So friends, definitely the
performance of the company is getting better quarter on quarter.   It seems so to
us.  Ok?  This meaning
is visible here.  So see
what is the special thing about an insurance company, which I have already
told you earlier because the
work done by these insurance companies is done on the asset
light model.  These cost
nothing, friends.  Just friends, the
inflow of money and cash keeps happening here.
Settlements mean much
less.  I mean, if 100
people deposit money here,
not everyone will make a claim.  Very few claims
come here.  So the majority of the money
goes into their pockets.  They make good
profits.  So due to which you
can see that the stock price is also
continuously in up trend here.
Although we have seen a slight decline
in market conditions from time to time, but
we are seeing good performance here in the long term.
Now if you see friends, the current
price here is around ₹234.  37 has a
P.  So friends, I think it is
available at a good valuation.  That's what
I feel like here right now.
Friends, here the
almost return on capital employed is 24, here the almost return
on equity is 25 and the return on equity is coming out to be 18.8%
and the debt to equity
ratio is almost zero here,
friends, it means it is completely
zero here.  So friends,
I feel that the valuations here are quite excellent.
Okay, if you look only on the basis of book value and current
price, then
if you look on the basis of book value, then the
stock seems a little expensive here.
But if you look at the valuation as per PE, then the
stock
is available at a good valuation.  Still,
I would recommend you to let the
stock price come down a bit,
friends.  Friends, you should invest here only when the stocks fall by 10-10%.
Because friends, there will
not be much momentum here right now because their
major quarter where there is good
sales has just passed.
So here
you may see a slight decline in the stock from now onwards.
After that you
can invest.  So friends, if you liked the content even a little bit
then like the video,
share it and subscribe to the channel.
I will meet you in the next video.   Please allow me till then.
Goodbye till then.  Take care and have a good time.  Thank
you very much to all of